Stephan Santos

SEATTLE, WA

CONTACT

stephan.pssantos@gmail.com (206) 307-4338 linkedin.com/in/stephan-santos/

SUMMARY: Software engineer with ~4 years of professional development work. Successfully delivered multiple individual and team projects, participating in every stage of the software development lifecycle from conception through to long-term end user support.

SKILLSET

LANGUAGES

C#, JavaScript, SQL, HTML/CSS

TOOLS & FRAMEWORKS

Node.js, .NET, PowerShell, Git, Docker, React, Blazor, OpenAPI, Postman, Adobe Creative Suite

SERVICES

Azure DevOps, Azure Cloud Services, Dynamics CRM, MS Power Platform, SharePoint

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

KING COUNTY (SEATTLE, WA)

| Senior Applications Developer | Jul 2021 – Apr 2022 |
|--------------------------------|---------------------|
| Journey Applications Developer | Oct 2019 – Jul 2021 |
| Web Developer | Jul 2018 – Oct 2019 |

- Worked projects in conjunction with an agile team to elicit and analyze requirements, develop code bases, configure CI/CD pipelines, write documentation, and track progress in project boards.
- Prepared data analytics dashboards and reports through Power BI and SSRS to streamline a group's data analytics pipeline and reduce delivery cost and time collectively by over 75%.
- Delivered a cloud-based web application that provided a self-service option when registering new legal documents, reducing administrative time for that step from potentially days to minutes.
- Facilitated the purchase and/or roll-out of commercial off-the-shelf software or SaaS products by evaluating the compatibility of the product with the organization's enterprise standards, coordinating integration work, organizing training, preparing communications, and preparing internal and end user documentation.

| COMPASS GROUP (REDMOND, WA) - Cook | Sep 2016 – Aug 2017 |
|--|----------------------|
| HB REALTY (SEATTLE, WA) - Property Manager | Oct 2015 – June 2016 |
| | Apr 2014 – Mar 2015 |

PERSONAL PROJECTS

"Okay" Online Message Board

Utilizes Azure B2C for local or social identity authentication. Containerized unit tested web API with API management front-end for token verification, rate limiting, etc. CI/CD pipelines via Azure DevOps. See the 'About' page (https://okay.stephansantos.com/about) for more implementation details.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

MICROSOFT CERTIFIED: AZURE DEVELOPER ASSOCIATE - Achieved February 2022 COMPTIA A+ - Achieved July 2019

ATENEO DE MANILA UNIVERSITY (QUEZON CITY, PHILIPPINES) - 2010-2014

- Graduated with a bachelor's degree in information design.
- Key Coursework: Web Development, Visual Communication, User Experience, Wireframing.